Aakash Singh

Full Stack Developer Montreal, QC

English, Hindi +1(514) 655-4805 aakash301098@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/aakash-singh-ba970822b/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Studying Programming and web technologies with specializing in Full Stack Web and Mobile application design and development. Studying all stages of the development cycle for dynamic projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including Javascript, Java, Python. Strong background in Web and Mobile Application Development with communication, collaboration, and problem-solving skills.

EXPERIENCE

PHP Developer

-- 10X0fy, Pune, IN

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

- Collaborate heavily with fellow developers, designers and analysts to solve problems.
- Be actively involved in all phases of software development(backend and frontend development), from requirements gathering to analysis, design, implementation, testing, migration and documentation.
- Develop complex consumer facing software using PHP, HTML/CSS, AJAX, JavaScript and associated technologies.
- Experience with version control, such as Git.
- Experience solving multi-browser compatibility and multi- device compatibility issues

SKILLS

- LANGUAGES: GO-LANG, JAVA, C++, C#.
- SCRIPTING LANGUAGES: JAVASCRIPT, PYTHON, PHP.
- **FRAMEWORK & LIBRARY**: REACT, EXPRESS-JS, NODE-JS, JAVA-ENTERPRISE, LARAVEL, .NET FRAMEWORK, FLUTTER, JQUERY, BOOTSTRAP.
- DATABASE: MONGO-DB, FIREBASE-DB, POSTGRESQL, PL SQL, SQL, MYSQL-SERVER, SQLite.
- **WEB TECHNOLOGIES:** HTML, CSS, PREPROCESSORS(SASS, PUG).
- VERSION CONTROL SYSTEM: GIT, GITHUB, BITBUCKET.
- **CLOUD PLATFORM:** HEROKU, DOCKER, GOOGLE-FIREBASE, AWS(AMAZON-WEB-SERVICES).
- **CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS:** WORDPRESS, DRUPAL.
- TOOLS: PHOTOSHOP, FIGMA.
- MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE: WORD, EXCEL, POWERPOINT, VISIO, OUTLOOK, ACCESS.
- **05:** ANDROID, IOS, WINDOWS, LINUX

PROJECTS / PORTFOLIOS

Social Networking
Website -

#Java, #HTML, #CSS, #Bootstrap

This website includes Friend requests, feeds, Likes, Chat, Delete Account, Clear

Account.

Dating Site -

#PHP, #MySQL #HTML, #CSS, #Bootstrap, #fontAwesome

Dating Website with features like Send Wink, Send Message, Add to Favourites & Notifications for Wink Seen, Added/Removed from

Favourites.

• Al Chatbot Application -

#Kotlin, #AndroidStudio, #API

A simple application ChatBot using BrainShop API that answers user's questions and also performs tasks such as opening Camera, sending Emails, taking Notes etc. with a Notes UI and management system integrated into it

Music Playlist -

#React, #Node.js, #API, #REST

A React Application to get Albums using Discogs API based on the artist entered in the search bar, and creating a playlist of favorites from it

<u>Ecommerce WebApp</u> -

#Go

This project deals with developing an ecommerce website for Online Product Sales. It provides the user with a catalog of different products available for purchase in the store. In order to facilitate online purchases, a shopping cart is provided to the user.

EDUCATION

Programming & Internet Technologies

Feb 2021 - May 2022

Attestation of College Studies

-- ISI, L'institut Supérieur d'Informatique, Montreal, CA

MAJOR: #ADVANCED-OOPS, #ALGORITHMS-AND-PROGRAMMING, #DATABASE, #SYSTEM-ANALYSIS, #MULTI-TIER-APPLICATIONS, #PYTHON, #ANDROID-APPLICATIONS, #WEB-SERVER-APPLICATION-DEVELOPMENT, #DESIGN-PATTERNS

Bachelor Of Computer Applications

SICSR, Pune, IN

June 2016 - May 2019

MAJOR: #DATA-STRUCTURE, #00PS C++, #FUNDAMENTALS-DBMS, #COMPUTER-SYSTEM-ORGANIZATION ARCHITECTURE, #RDBMS, #DISCRETE-MATHEMATICS, #JAVA-PROGRAMMING, #SYSTEM-ANALYSIS-DESIGN, #SOFTWARE-ENGINEERING, #ASP.NET, #E-COMMERCE, #OPERATING-SYSTEM.

OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Warehouse Clerk

-- SSENSE, Montreal, CA

Dec 2021 - Present

- Managed and Organized shipments based on priority
- Operated a Compacter to handle waste(Cardboard boxes, wrapping plastic, etc.)
- Basic problem-solving in case any items are missing
- Sorted and arranged items based on multiple factors
- Communicated to supervisors and team-leads to report progress

